Preliminary Inventory of the Poland. Rada Narodowa. Records, 1940-1945
Hoover Institution Archives
Poland. Rada Narodowa. Records,
1940-1945
76053
Poland. Rada Narodowa.
11 manuscript boxes (4.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Decrees, reports, stenographic records, minutes of meetings, and speeches, relating to political developments in Poland and Eastern Europe, and to activities of the Polish Government-in-Exile.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1976.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Governments in exile.; World War, 1939-1945--Poland.; Poland.; Poland--History--Occupation, 1939-1945.
Container List
- Archives of the Polish National Council (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - First Council
    - Plenary Sessions - opening session, 1940 January 23 (order of the day, speeches, motions) (8 typewritten and mimeographed items, 27 pages. List included)
    - Presidium of Council - records of meetings, 1941 March 22-July 3 (10 typewritten items, 12 pages. List included) (Folder 2)
    - Commissions (Folder 3)
      - Legal-Constitutional Commission - stenographic records of meetings, 1940 March 4-1941 July 10 (13 typewritten items, 74 pages. List included
      - Commission on Budget and Economical Affairs (Folder 4)
        - Part I Stenographic records of meetings, 1940 March 4-1941 March 13 (32 typewritten items, 606 pages. List included)
        - Part II Drafts, motions, and reports concerning budget of 1940 and 1941 (169 typewritten and mimeographed items, 203 pages. List included) (Folder 5)
      - Commission on Foreign Affairs - stenographic records of meetings, 1940 March 4-1941 July 10 (13 typewritten items, 131 pages. List included) (Folder 6)
      - Commission on Military Affairs - stenographic records of meetings, 1940 March 4-1941 February 10 (15 typewritten items, 197 pages. List included) (Folder 7)
      - Commission on Emigration - stenographic records of meetings, 1940 August 26-1941 May 29 (4 typewritten items, 50 pages. List included) (Folder 8)
  - Second Council (Folder 9)
    - Plenary Sessions
      - Documents concerning the convocation of the II National Council (6 typewritten items. List included)
      - Stenographic records of meetings (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - Meetings 1-34, 1942 February 24-July 14 (34 typewritten items. List included)
        - Meetings 35-69, 1942 July 18-1943 March 30 (36 typewritten items. List of items in Folder 10) (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - Meetings 70-99, 1943 April 1-October 8 (34 typewritten items. List of items in Folder 10) (Box 3-4, Folder 12)
        - Meetings 100-129, 1943 December 2-1944 May 19 (30 typewritten items. List of items in Folder 10) (Box 4-5, Folder 13)
        - Meetings 130-161, 1944 May 26-1945 January 5 (31 typewritten items. List of items in Folder 10) (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Presidium of Council - records of meetings, 1942 March 16-1944 December 12 (89 typewritten items, 102 pages. List of items included) (Folder 15)
    - Commissions (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - List of Commissions and its members (6 mimeographed items, 6 pages. List of items included)
      - Legal-Constitutional Commission - stenographic records of meetings, 1942 March 11-1945 February 23 (61 typewritten items. List of items included) (Folder 17)
      - Commission on Budget and Economical Affairs (Folder 18)
        - Part I Stenographic records of meetings, 1942 March 11-1944 December 22
          - 1942 March 14-1943 March 1 (54 typewritten items. List included)
          - 1943 March 2-1944 December 21 (88 typewritten items. List of items included in Folder 18) (Box 7, Folder 19)
        - Part II Drafts, motions, and reports concerning Budget of 1942, 1943, 1944 (56 typewritten and mimeographed items. List of items included) (Folder 20)
      - Commission on Foreign Affairs - stenographic records of meetings, 1942 March 11-1945 March 14 (26 typewritten items. List of items included) (Folder 21)
      - Commission on Military Affairs - stenographic records of meetings, 1942 March 11-1945 January 31 (40 typewritten items. List of items included) (Box 8, Folder 22)
      - Special Commission on War Budget - minutes of meetings, 1942 April 13-1943 December 25 (4 typewritten items. List of items included) (Folder 23)
      - Special Commission - Inquiry on Treatment of Jews in the Polish Army - stenographic records of meetings, 1944 May 17-1945 January 29 (20 typewritten items. List of items included) (Folder 24)
    - Bulletins (2 items, dated 1942 October 30 and 1943 February 1. Mimeographed) (Folder 25)
  - Documents pertaining to I and II Council (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Reports of Commissions, 1940-1944
      - a Legal-Constitutional Commission (19 items)
      - b Commission on Foreign Affairs (5 items)
      - c Commission on Military Affairs (5 items)
      - d Social-Economical Commission (1 item) List of items included
    - Interpellations to the Government (31 typewritten items. 33 pages. List of items included) (Folder 27)
    - Motions presented by Members of Council, 1940-1944 (98 typewritten and mimeographed items. 85 pages. List of items included) (Folder 28)
    - Resolutions - proposed, 1940-1944 (62 typewritten and mimeographed items 37 pages. List of items included) (Folder 29)
    - Resolutions - adopted, 1940-1943 (45 typewritten and mimeographed items. 69 pages. List of items included) (Folder 30)
    - Decrees of the President of the Republic - drafts and definite texts (49 typewritten and mimeographed items. List of items included) (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Reports and speeches - Plenary Sessions and Commissions (27 typewritten and mimeographed items. List of items included) (Folder 32)
  - Miscellaneous documents and papers (Folder 33)
    - Papers concerning relations with Czechoslovak National Council (7 typewritten and mimeographed items. List of items included)
    - Various materials - reports of Ministries, press reports, correspondence, etc. (63 typewritten and mimeographed items. List of items included) (Folder 34)
  - Stenography of the First National Council (Émigré Parliament) (Box 10)
    - Dekret Prezydenta Rzeczpospolitej z dnia 9.XII. 1939 r. o Radzie Narodowej Rzeczpospolitej Polskiej (1 copy)
    - Spis czlonkow Pierwszej Rady Narodowej (1 copy)
    - Stenogramy posiedzen Rady Narodowej (No 1, 2, 3, 4, 4a, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 9a, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15)
    - Stenogram z konferencji Rady Narodowej odbytej dnia 19 VI. 1940 w Libourne - upadek Francji (1 copy
    - Stenogram z konferencji Rady Narodowej odbytej dnia 7 VII. 1940 w Londynie - pierwsze zebranie na ziemi angielskiej (1 copy)
    - Stenogramy posiedzen Rady Narodowej (No 16. 17, 18)
    - Stenogramy posiedzen Rady Narodowej (No 19 - film wykonany ze skrotu posiedzenia, zalaczony z pudeleczku zel.)
    - Stenogramm No 20 missing (even in the original)
    - Stenogramy posiedzen Rady Narodowej (No 21, 21a, 22, 23, 23a, 24, 25, 25a, 25b, 25c, 25d, 25e, 26, 27, 27a, 27b, 28, 28a, 28b, 29, 30, 31, 32, 32a, 33, 34, 34a, 34b, 34c, 34d, 34e, 34f, 34g, 34h, 34i, 35, 36, 37, 38, 39, 40, 40a, 41, 41a, 42, 43)
  - Minutes of meetings, 1940-1941 (Box 11)